<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Pragmatic Mentor</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/</link><description>My Journey towards Becoming a Better Mentor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:48:39 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MLaaS vs MLOps</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2023-02-01-mlaas-vs-mlops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:48:39 +0800</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2023-02-01-mlaas-vs-mlops/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I watched this interesting video regarding the differences of MLOps (e.g. Train, Serve, Monitor your own model) vs ML-as-a-Service (e.g. Foundation Models).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AK1jWpLm2Ao" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MLOps vs ML-As-Service // Jill Chase and Manmeet Gujral</a></p>
<p>These are some interesting learning points:</p>
<ul>
<li>MLaaS tend to be more B2C and MLOps is mainly B2B</li>
<li>Foundation Models have pushed the MLOps Frameworks to emphasize on the software&rsquo;s ability to perform fine-tuning</li>
<li>MLOps revenue generation is not as fast as MLaaS but the contracts and projects are bigger</li>
<li>MLOps tends to lean towards providing for instances of Proprietary Data.</li>
</ul>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AK1jWpLm2Ao" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description></item><item><title>Functional Frameworks in Machine Learning</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2022-12-02-functional-programming-in-ml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 10:50:57 +0800</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2022-12-02-functional-programming-in-ml/</guid><description><![CDATA[This is my conversation with OpenAI&rsquo;s ChatGPT. I want to clarify I have no intention of using this technology for monotization. I&rsquo;ve used it for generating knowledge and nothing else.
Functional Frameworks Are a Thing Q: I&rsquo;ve been noticing machine learning frameworks such as JAX and functorch have been adopting functional programming paradigms. Is this true?
Yes, it&rsquo;s true that some machine learning frameworks are adopting functional programming paradigms. This is because functional programming can help make it easier to write code that is concise, modular, and reusable, which can be useful when working on large machine learning projects.]]></description></item><item><title>Information- Processing, Organization and Retrieval</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2022-11-17-information-proc-org-rec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 17:11:30 +0800</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2022-11-17-information-proc-org-rec/</guid><description>What do you store and how do you store it so later you can retrieve it ?
What am I sharing ? I have a problem with finding the right information from the raw data I receive, organizing that information and also being able to retrieve the information in an optimal manner.
Let me give you an example to clarify a bit more.
Example Scenario: Daily Standup Scenario: I have a standup meeting with my team almost every day.</description></item><item><title>Found It!: Software Engineering at Google</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2021-11-24-software-eng-at-google/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 16:03:28 +0800</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2021-11-24-software-eng-at-google/</guid><description><![CDATA[In my last post, I was shared what my concerns were regarding software development and what my role as a Tech Lead should look at AISG.
Today, I had an awesome find!
One thing led to another I was looking at my youtube subscriptions, and I saw video posted on the &ldquo;Dev Interrupted&rdquo; channel. If you aren&rsquo;t subscribed to it, I highly recommend it. I recall I found the channel when Luca Rossi, the owner of the amazing &ldquo;Refactoring&rdquo; newsletter, mentioned it in one of the issues of his newsletter (Thanks Luca!]]></description></item><item><title>Being a Tech Lead at AISG</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2021-11-22-being-a-tech-lead-at-aisg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 16:18:45 +0800</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2021-11-22-being-a-tech-lead-at-aisg/</guid><description><![CDATA[It&rsquo;s been a year since I joined AI Singapore and I&rsquo;m grateful for the experience so far. I&rsquo;ve been on a few projects up until now and gathered a lot of experience. My journey, however, is far from over and I have many things to learn.
What am I suppose to do? I remember when I started my job, I asked my supervisor: What is my role as a &ldquo;Senior Engineer&rdquo;?]]></description></item><item><title>Breaking the Code to Learn</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-11-25-breaking-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-11-25-breaking-to-learn/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new job at AI Singapore. The nature of the job is in a way that I have to mentor people and guide them to be better AI Engineers.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I think my blog posts will be more relevant and useful.
Today, I want to touch upon a topic that came to my mind when I was thinking about how to teach people whether there ML system is robust enough or not.</description></item><item><title>Challenge: Decision Making</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-06-30-challenge-decision-making/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-06-30-challenge-decision-making/</guid><description>In this blog I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss one of the most difficult challenge that any architect will come across in their path to becoming professional: deciding on design and toold choices. For myself, this challenge reoccurs more and more often becuase of my own tendancy to making sure that my design is right and that I&amp;rsquo;m using the right tools. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better that I delve into what I mean with an example.</description></item><item><title>The Beginning</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-04-03-the-beginning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-04-03-the-beginning/</guid><description><![CDATA[I really don&rsquo;t know what title I can put on myself. Although, in my current comapny, I am considered to be the Lead AI Scientist but to be honest, I don&rsquo;t know what that means.
My background is machine learning and deep learning. I have worked on multiple aread of machine learning (some which I don&rsquo;t have a paper). In my master&rsquo;s thesis, I was using machine learning to differentiate between a special type of evoked potentials in the brain called the &ldquo;Error Potential&rdquo;.]]></description></item></channel></rss>