<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Machine Learning - Category -</title><link>/categories/machine-learning/</link><description>Machine Learning - Category -</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:48:39 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MLaaS vs MLOps</title><link>/posts/2023-02-01-mlaas-vs-mlops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:48:39 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/2023-02-01-mlaas-vs-mlops/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I watched this interesting video regarding the differences of MLOps (e.g. Train, Serve, Monitor your own model) vs ML-as-a-Service (e.g. Foundation Models).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AK1jWpLm2Ao"target="_blank" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer">MLOps vs ML-As-Service // Jill Chase and Manmeet Gujral</a></p>
<p>These are some interesting learning points:</p>
<ul>
<li>MLaaS tend to be more B2C and MLOps is mainly B2B</li>
<li>Foundation Models have pushed the MLOps Frameworks to emphasize on the software&rsquo;s ability to perform fine-tuning</li>
<li>MLOps revenue generation is not as fast as MLaaS but the contracts and projects are bigger</li>
<li>MLOps tends to lean towards providing for instances of Proprietary Data.</li>
</ul>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->]]></description></item><item><title>Functional Frameworks in Machine Learning</title><link>/posts/2022-12-02-functional-programming-in-ml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 10:50:57 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/2022-12-02-functional-programming-in-ml/</guid><description><![CDATA[This is my conversation with OpenAI&rsquo;s ChatGPT. I want to clarify I have no intention of using this technology for monotization. I&rsquo;ve used it for generating knowledge and nothing else.
Functional Frameworks Are a Thing Q: I&rsquo;ve been noticing machine learning frameworks such as JAX and functorch have been adopting functional programming paradigms. Is this true?
Yes, it&rsquo;s true that some machine learning frameworks are adopting functional programming paradigms. This is because functional programming can help make it easier to write code that is concise, modular, and reusable, which can be useful when working on large machine learning projects.]]></description></item></channel></rss>