<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>ML Architect - Tag - The Pragmatic Mentor</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/tags/ml-architect/</link><description>ML Architect - Tag - The Pragmatic Mentor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/tags/ml-architect/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking the Code to Learn</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-11-25-breaking-to-learn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-11-25-breaking-to-learn/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new job at AI Singapore. The nature of the job is in a way that I have to mentor people and guide them to be better AI Engineers.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I think my blog posts will be more relevant and useful.
Today, I want to touch upon a topic that came to my mind when I was thinking about how to teach people whether there ML system is robust enough or not.</description></item><item><title>Challenge: Decision Making</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-06-30-challenge-decision-making/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-06-30-challenge-decision-making/</guid><description>In this blog I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss one of the most difficult challenge that any architect will come across in their path to becoming professional: deciding on design and toold choices. For myself, this challenge reoccurs more and more often becuase of my own tendancy to making sure that my design is right and that I&amp;rsquo;m using the right tools. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better that I delve into what I mean with an example.</description></item><item><title>The Beginning</title><link>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-04-03-the-beginning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Siavash Sakhavi</author><guid>https://blog.siavashsakhavi.com/2020-04-03-the-beginning/</guid><description><![CDATA[I really don&rsquo;t know what title I can put on myself. Although, in my current comapny, I am considered to be the Lead AI Scientist but to be honest, I don&rsquo;t know what that means.
My background is machine learning and deep learning. I have worked on multiple aread of machine learning (some which I don&rsquo;t have a paper). In my master&rsquo;s thesis, I was using machine learning to differentiate between a special type of evoked potentials in the brain called the &ldquo;Error Potential&rdquo;.]]></description></item></channel></rss>