<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Engineering on The Pragmatic Mentor</title><link>https://www.pragmatic-mentor.xyz/categories/software-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Software Engineering on The Pragmatic Mentor</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 11:11:54 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pragmatic-mentor.xyz/categories/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hobbies vs Professional Development</title><link>https://www.pragmatic-mentor.xyz/posts/2023-03-09-hobby-vs-professional/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 11:11:54 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.pragmatic-mentor.xyz/posts/2023-03-09-hobby-vs-professional/</guid><description>This is a very beautiful and interesting video from Dave Farley. I love the guy for his insights.
When it comes to development, it&amp;rsquo;s very important to do exploratory learning via hobbies to learn general matters. However, It&amp;rsquo;s only when we do professional development based on the requirements of stakeholder that we learn the most and high quality code.
This is a selling point for the AI Singapore AIAP program, especially the 100E Program.</description></item><item><title>Code Aesthetics</title><link>https://www.pragmatic-mentor.xyz/posts/2023-02-02-code-aesthetic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 15:08:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.pragmatic-mentor.xyz/posts/2023-02-02-code-aesthetic/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was going through my twitter feed and saw uncle bob sharing a youtube video on &amp;ldquo;never nesters&amp;rdquo;.
When I saw the &amp;ldquo;never nesters&amp;rdquo; title, I thought to myself that this is possibly a video about code styles or how to
write clean code. Out of curioisty I went to the youtube channel and, lo and behold, I had found a gold mine: &lt;strong>Code Aesthetic&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This channel has done a few special things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It has explained problems with code from both a aesthetic point of view and also, from a technical point of view&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I love the simplicity of the video in terms of the content of each frame. You can read the code snippets and follow through the changes that are going to be eventually made.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The videos question some of the &amp;ldquo;norms&amp;rdquo; in coding. For example, the concept of &amp;ldquo;writing comments to explain code&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I immediately suscribed and added it to my Mailbrew Youtube list. I recommend you suscribe as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CodeAesthetic" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">https://www.youtube.com/@CodeAesthetic&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>